The SCOAN Sunday Service
Happy New Year!
Thank you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You may be seated, thank you.
I know - because you see me in what you are wearing everyday.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Don't worry - next week you will see me wearing 'Agbada' (Nigerian robe).
Even wearing this I am not comfortable enough.
I need to get used to it.
Good morning!
Wow.
Happy New Year!
A New Beginning!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Viewers, Happy New Year!
A New Beginning!
Take it; believe it.
When you say, "Happy New Year!", you are talking of faith.
You want to wine and dine with God – faith.
Only faith pleases Him – no alternative – no shortcut.
God wants to be involved in our lives as mother's.
Tell your neighbour, "God wants to be involved in our lives as mother's".
You know mother - good mother...
God is concerned about you; He is concerned about us.
He wants to be involved as a mother in our lives.
We just have to allow Him by faith.
Allow Him; that is why He tells us to pray.
The case now is: prayer is a work of faith.
You can't just rise and...
Christians we have today, all over the world, - we have a lot of challenges.
We can be a man of prayer but perhaps not a man of faith.
Tell your neighbour, "You can be a man of prayer but perhaps not a man of faith".
Tell your neighbour again.
(You can be a man of prayer but perhaps not a man of faith.)
I can't hear you.
So, when you see your neighbour... he can be a man of prayer but perhaps not a man of faith.
That is the problem.
That is just the problem - you don't know who is praying.
You can be a man of prayer but perhaps not a man of faith.
This is what happens all over the world today - you see people; "fire, prayer in your house..."
Who is praying?
When you are a man of prayer and not a man of faith, you are saying words.
Tell your neighbour.
You are saying words when you are a man of prayer and not a man of faith.
You are saying words.
But when you are a man of prayer and a man of faith, you are praying prayer.
You can be saying words -
that is, you are talking to yourself and talking to people around you but not God.
Saying words is different from praying prayer.
Millions of prayers are prayed with almost no faith.
I repeat again: "Millions of prayers are prayed with almost no faith".
The SCOAN Sunday Service
This is what is happening; this is why there is no result.
This is why people shout - this is about prayers in churches everywhere; but the effect we cannot see.
Millions of prayers are prayed with almost no faith.
Overflow Congregation
So, it is possible...
So, when you see praying people - be conscious - is it really a man of faith?
Because you can be a man of prayer and perhaps not a man of faith.
You can be a woman of prayer and perhaps not a woman of faith.
When you are a woman of prayer and not a woman of faith, you are saying words -
that is, you talk.
You talk to people: people around you will hear you, "she is praying", and you inside will hear yourself, but God...
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Sometimes it is very frustrating to be talking to someone who is not a man of faith.
This is why we allow testimonies of people...
The Bible says when you see God as reliable, you put your trust in Him.
Ha - He is reliable, He can do it for me.
He has done it for this person, I can see what God had done - that is greater from what I am looking for.
"He had given a greater blessing to this person but I am looking for a small one - He will do it for me."
You put your trust in Him.
If you pay attention to God's Word, you will find that faith comes spontaneously.
Pay attention with all your heart.
It is that simple.
When you look at your Bible, you would agree with me: no faith, no God for you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Open your Bible at the Book of Luke 8:25 - hear God's Word.
WHERE IS YOUR FAITH?
That is the language.
Luke 8:25
He says, "Where is your faith? If I cannot find your faith I cannot talk to you. If I talk to you you cannot receive."
WHERE IS YOUR FAITH?
I am here today to ask you: where is your faith?
Look at Luke 8:25.
WHERE IS YOUR FAITH?
Let someone say, "Where is your faith?"
(Where is your faith?)
It is like, "Where is your Bible?"
The SCOAN Sunday Service
That is God's Word.
Where is your faith?
The SCOAN Sunday Service
In Mark 4:40; we hear what God said there.
He said, "Do you still have no faith?"
After having met them many times: "Do you still have no faith?"
It is for you to know the importance of it.
Do you still have no faith?
Ask your neighbour.
(Do you still have no faith?)
That is the question here.
In every area.
When you look at the Book of John 20:27 - it says, "Stop doubting and believe."
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The worst one in the Book of Mark 16:14 - it says, "When He saw their lack of faith, He rebuked them."
Cast them...
The SCOAN Sunday Service
He said, "Aa, they have no faith" - He rebuked them.
He knew they were not for Him and they cannot ever be before Him without faith.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
So, therefore...
When you see people praying, it would be too early for you to say, "He is a child of God, or "A woman of faith",
because one can be a woman of prayer but perhaps not a woman of faith.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
It is difficult; people don't know.
People believe that once you pray you pray - no.
Saying words is different from praying prayer.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Let us think about it and stop wasting your time.
You say, "I pray and no answer or result", while you are saying words.
When you are talking you are saying words and you say you pray.
Saying words is different from praying prayer.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You say, "I fast" - the same thing.
You can be fasting and that is for you and people around you.
God is a cheerful giver.
He wants to heal, bless and deliver you because He is so much concerned about you.
He loves you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
To reach Him, prayer is the master key and prayer is a work of faith.
Find time, sit down and meditate over this - that, "I am just a woman of prayer, not a woman of faith.
I am just saying words, not praying prayer. I am just talking to people and myself. Not to God.
What a shameful thing; very embarrassing. I thought I was praying to God."
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Now - to have faith...
If you pay attention, you would find that faith comes spontaneously, that is, naturally.
Attention - what is attention?
All your heart, your soul.
All your heart; you listen to what they are saying.
Not to hear and monitor your business at the same time, instead of leaving your business for God.
So, I hear here and my mind is also over there.
All your heart.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You have to be very inquisitive.
Find out the truth and the truth will set you free.
Don't just take everything you hear.
Don't just take everything you hear and see; you must examine them in the light of God's Word.
To examine things in the light of God's Word is to ask, "God, what is this? God, what is that? God tell me more".
Examine everything.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
We have come a long way.
You have been to many places – a lot of places of worship.
You have seen enough.
Having seen enough is to be able to discern the truth from the false.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
God loves you.
(Amen.)
How do you know God loves you?
When you don't love Him and He loves you, how will you appreciate this?
You say "Amen."
How, can somebody...?
Tell me how do you know God loves you?
Without correspondence.
If I love you and don't love me, what kind of love is that?
No correspondence.
I love you and you don't love me.
... by your way, action, attitude - you don't love me.
What kind of love is that?
If I love you and you don’t respond, what kind of love is that?
It is not a good love.
That is the love you have for God.
We seem to be more of His enemy than His friend.
More of His enemy than His what?
His friend.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Our challenges that are supposed to draw us close to God,
seem to take us off, take us away from God and that is the purpose of challenges.
The purpose of challenges is to draw us close.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Your challenges, whatever you are going through -
sickness, hardship, setback, just name whatever you are going through -
are to draw you closer to Him but opposite is the case today.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
How many years are we taking to find out the truth?
For how long shall we continue finding out the truth?
Is it God, is it this, is it a challenge, is it devil - for how long?
The SCOAN Sunday Service
What we received last year - where is it?
What are you asking for?
What we are asking for today are those things we have received in the past but we lack maintenance.
God wants to do awesome things but because of lack of dynamic faith,
those things cannot be done through us.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Lack of dynamic faith limits what God can do through us.
Faith is like coins – Heavenly currency.
How much you have is how much you get.
When you go to the market with million dollars, you cannot get more than this money in the market.
What you have is what you get.
This faith we talk about is Heavenly currency to get Heavenly resources.
Healing, salvation, blessing, breakthrough; we get them, we buy them.
You can purchase Heavenly resources with Heavenly currency.
How much you get is how much you obtain.
Your faith took you here today.
Will the same faith also get you what you want here?
How much will this faith obtain?
That is it.
Your faith got you here today.
Look at the analysis I have given you.
The voice of God - it says, "Where is your faith?"
That shows, if you don't have faith, He cannot address you.
Where is your faith?
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Do you still have no faith?
That is - after much addressing, teaching, messages, going to churches, you are a Christian - yet
you still have no faith?
That is the question.
Stop doubting and believe.
Because of lack of faith, He rebuked brethren in the Book of Mark 16:14.
He rebuked them.
You are a satan, you are a devil - get behind me.
And I say, "Don't let us waste our time".
If you know how to pray and you are buying a book which teaches you how to pray...
You can be a woman of prayer but perhaps not a woman of faith.
Many of you have books that teach you...
When you are praying you have your own words.
You can be a woman of prayer but perhaps not a woman of faith
and if you pray without faith, you are saying words.
You can now think of challenges you have been facing.
Pray pray pray...
It may be you are saying words and not praying prayer.